So we are going to be creating configuration profile in regards to endpoint protection policy.
So if you're working for a company and you've not been using Microsoft Intune probably you'll be using group policies.
Sometimes we use group policy to utterly create a policy that will prevent the user from doing some things or blocking some assets to some applications or even controlling the firewall.
So if I go to my on the devices and I go to Windows and on our windows you can see we have a call the configuration profile.
On our configuration profile we can actually create different kind of profile.
Well I'm going to click create profile and I'm going to select in Windows 10.
I'll let that with me is Windows 10. I'm both the 10 or Windows 11.
So here we have the profile type. I'm going to select templates and on the template you can see we have a lot of pre-configured templates.
We can use at this moment I'm actually interested in the endpoint protection.
So let me just click on that and then click create.
So by clicking create a more color we just call this test 01 and then click nest.
So on the configuration profile you can see we have different configuration.
We can actually modify it. For example we have the Windows Defender guide. I don't even say it's a most configured.
But if I go to the Windows Defender firewall here you can see it's not configured file transfer protocol.
We can already say to say one to allow or one to block file transfer protocol.
Appreciate key coding. It says it's not configured certificates.
You can see that's another configure. So I'll click configure the file transfer protocol.
And then here we can we now have like Windows encryption.
I'm going to click on see encrypt the files we can totally say as well.
Want to acquire that at the files I encrypt.
Want to also beat lock up base with you for all that this execution.
Can I tell you block that what I can also say is configure a crucial method.
Here you can see select enable allows you to configure a crucial method for OS drive fees data.
Removeable drive will gradually sick enabled.
And then a crucial type a crucial for princess them device.
You can see we have the different piece we can't really use.
So let me just leave that for the thoughts.
And it says beat lock hour is drive settings on the additional start-off.
We can see one to acquire and then beat lock hour with no comfortable TPM.
Not configured. So here you can see we have a different configuration.
We can't really configure for just the beat lock hour alone.
And also you can see we have like the windows defender and the windows defender credential guide.
So after you've checked and measure that you've configured all what you need to configure.
Now we can now click nest.
And on our next you can set our totally assigned to group out to all users or out all devices.
And then we can now click nest.
And also you see the rule one can say assign profile if, for example, the OS or the OS version is, you know,
you can actually decide to showcase you want to apply this rule if only your princess stem version is the following.
But at the moment I'm going to do the desktop number.
I totally deploy this profile.
I created. So let me just click nest.
I have a controller through what's created before we know his secret but another profile be created.
And if applied central devices is going to take some time for the profile to start taking effect on those other devices.
It's not going to take effect immediately but at some time you can start taking effect.